# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 前段时间有很多粉丝在问
Previously there are many fans asking
# 这个鱼片切出来会不会里面有刺
If there are many fishbones in fish slices
# 会不会吃了卡喉咙
would its bones get stuck in throat
# 今天我就杀条鱼
I’m going to slice this fish
# 给你们解决这个疑惑
to address your concerns
# 先放血
Let’s bleed this fish
# 好 放好血之后我们来打鳞
Okay, after the fish bleeds out, clean its scales
# 其实我们正常来说
Honestly to me
# 按照以前我的速度杀一条鱼的话
Gutter a fish at my regular pace
# 也就两三分钟吧
In just 2 or 3 minutes
# 两三分钟是把它杀好洗干净
I can gutter and clean fish in 2 to 3 minutes
# 去鱼鳞去鱼肚
Including clean fish scales and its maw
# 然后再把它剁出来
and cut it to slices
# 如果不起片的情况下
If my kitchen knife holds well
# 好 我拿去洗一下
Oaky I am going to wash it
# 然后把这个鱼擦一下
And dry the fish
# 首先从这里切一刀跟鲤鱼是一样的
Fist of all, slice here, same as how I cut carp
# 然后往上面走
Then cut all the away up
# 你们新手一定要拿个毛巾来
Amateurs need a towel to grasp
# 因为这个鱼比较滑
Because the fish is slippery
# 然后翻过来
Then flip it over
# 这个就晚上拿给你做水煮鱼吃
I am going to cook “Shui Zhu fish” (lit. Spicy Boiled fish slices) for you tonight（可添加对译表）
# 可以安
Great
# 好 这个鱼片就解出来了
Okay, now we got the fish slices
# 我们片鱼的时候
When we slice the fish
# 这样子压着
Press it down like this
# 同样也是（讲过的）这个就不教了
Same as I showed before, not going to teach again
# 上次都看过了
We have learned before
# 好 鱼皮我们就片出来了
Okay, we have sliced the fish
# 现在我们的鱼片
Now our fish
# 片成这种一片一片的了
is cut into slices like this
# 这么厚
Thick as such
# 这中间有没有鱼刺
Then is there fishbone in the slices?
# 我跟大家说这里面是有鱼刺的
I want to let you know there is
# 但是它这个鱼刺不长
But the fishbone is tiny
# 来 我们把它煮熟一片
Okay, let's cook one slice
# 然后把它碾碎了
And ground it
# 看一下里面的鱼刺到底有多长
To check how long the fishbone is
# 看 都熟了
Look, it is all cooked
# 肯定撒 没得好大一片嘛
Of course, it is a large piece
# 好了 我们这个鱼片已经焯好水出来了
Oaky, we have fish slices scalded
# 就是已经熟了
It is well cooked
# 现在我们把这个鱼片把它弄开
Now we are going to ground the fish
# 我们来看一下里面到底有没有刺
Let’s see if there are fishbones
# ok 找到一根刺了
okay, find one
# 有是有 很短
There are some, but short
# 这根
This one
# 所以的话
In conclusion
# 我们通过这次实验找出来的刺当中
We have found fishbones in this experiment
# 斜刀的有比较长的
Slant-cut leaves long fish bones
# 我建议你们普通家庭里面切这个鱼片
I would recommend when you slice fish at home
# 直刀往下面切 切薄一点
Cut even more straight and thinner
# 它的鱼刺就鱼片多厚
The thickness of fish slice
# 鱼刺就有多长
Determines the length of fishbones
# 因为它的刺的话它是斜着长的
Because its bones are naturally at an angle
# 你又正好斜着片
And if you are slant cutting
# 它里面肯定有稍微长一点的刺
It will leave longer fishbone
# 如果是竖着切的话
If you would cut straight
# 它的刺就相当于是这样横着切断了
The fishbone will be cut off horizontally
# 如果你们想吃
If you are craving
# 确实是想吃
Really craving for fish
# 没有多少刺的话
With less fishbones
# 可以换鱼换成鲈鱼啊
You can choose bass fish over carp
# 比如一些海鱼
or some deep-sea fishes
# 它的刺就非常少
which have less fish bones
# 下面开始今天真正的表演“松鼠鱼”
Next is today’s real cooking show for “squirrel fish”
# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 今天我用这条草鱼做一个松鼠鱼
I am going to cook the dish with this grass carp
# 给我四伯吃
For my uncle
# 我们先来说下这个草鱼放血怎么放
Let’s see how to bleed the grass carp
# 一般就是用一只手抓住它
Usually just grasp it with one hand
# 然后用这个尖刀
Then use a short knife
# 把这个他它前面这个鱼鳞刮掉
Scrape off the scales here
# 然后就在这个位置
Then at this point
# 这个位置
Right here
# 这是它的心脏
Here is its heart
# 一下子就流出来了
It bleeds right away
# 这条鱼小它没有什么血
It’s a small fish with not much blood
# 所有的鱼当中这个草鱼的鳞是最好打的
Out of all fishes, it is easiest to scrape the scales of grass carp
# 吃鱼就要吃这种 小个点的
Ideal fish to eat, smaller one
# 斤多点的这种
Fish with a couple jins (500g)
# 草鱼就要吃两斤多三斤以下的
Grass carp around 2 or 3 jin is the best
# 然后我们这个鱼跟前面鲤鱼是一样的
And it's the same way of handling the previous carp
# 右手掐右边的腮
Use your right hand to grab and remove the gill on the right side
# 然后这样清洗干净就可以
Wash and tidy up like this
# 好 我们这个鱼洗了
Okay, our fish has been washed
# 然后要用这个毛巾把它擦干净
Now I'm gonna wipe it clean and dry with this towel
# 要不然的话
Otherwise
# 这个鱼在菜板上要动要滑
It's gonna slip on the chopping board
# 如果你们家里没有多余的毛巾用来擦的话
If you don't have extra towel for this
# 用刀刮一下也行
It's ok to scrape it with a knife
# 把它的头取下来
Take off its head
# 同样的是要贴着骨头走
The same way, cut as close to the bone as possible
# 大家可以看到这个骨头就出来了
As you can see, the bone is separated (from the meat)
# 出来了之后呢
And then
# 把它这里剁开
Chop here
# 肚子上的骨头去下来
and remove the bone near its belly
# 这样子就可以取下来这个肉
In this way the meat can be cut off
# 其实我们这个刀法怎么切都可以
Actually you can slice as the way you like
# 但是其中一刀必须要斜刀切
But you must take slant cut at least once
# 要刚好切到鱼皮的位置
Cut as close to the fish skin as possible
# 第二刀可以用直刀切
You can cut straight when you are doing the other direction
# 好了 我们这个就切好了
Cool. Now we're done with cutting
# 这个脑壳光秃秃（没有肉）的有啥子吃法嘛
This head is so bold and barely has any meat. How're ya gonna eat it?
# 这个是拿来摆起好看的
It is used to decorating the dish for a better serving look
# 做好了之后我们下面来上粉（淀粉）
Cutting finished. We next wrap the fish with starch
# 四伯爷等会你看到放粉不要骂人哦
Uncle don't scold me when you see the amount of starch I use
# 然后我们漏2个蛋黄
We take 2 egg yolks
# 我们这个只要蛋黄
Only yolk is needed for this dish
# 就是为了让鱼肉炸出来
In order that the fish can be fried
# 更酥脆一些
more crispy
# 然后我们把这个洗好挤干水份的鱼丢进来
And we drop this fish in. It has been washed and the water has been squeezed out
# 还有这个鱼头
And this fish head
# 给它拌一下
Mix it a bit
# 四伯爷帮我拿点盐巴来
Uncle, can you take me some salt
# 来嘛 四伯爷给我放一点
Come on uncle, spread some salt for me
# 好嘛
Okay
# 放滴点儿的
Add a little bit
# 好好好
Okayyyyy
# 够了够了够了
This is enough
# 多多少少 鱼要咸点的
Fish would need more salt
# 咸点可以
It won't do much harm to use more salt!
# 我们给它上一下底味
Let's do some basic seasoning
# 我伯爷说要咸一点
My uncle asks for more salt
# 咸一点的话其实也还好
Hmm, I'm ok with a saltier fish
# 没什么问题
Not a big problem
# 这个盐不是调咸味
But adding this salt is not for its own flavour
# 主要是让这个糖更加的突出这个甜味
It's for highlighting the sweet taste of sugar
# 看嘛 这个粉
See, the starch
# 但是要不了这么多
But I'm not using so much yet
# 先少抓一点
Grab some at first
# 给它上一下
Wrap the fish in it
# 简单先上一下
Just simply
# 再换一个盆
Then change to the other tray
# 所以做这个菜有点亏（费）粉安
That's why making this dish is a hugh expense of starch
# 是这个原因
It's for this reason
# 把这个给它放进去
Drop the fish in
# 看 四伯爷
See, uncle
# 还整得安逸
Ehem it looks nice
# 好 可以了
Ok, it's finished
# 要的 走嘛四伯爷
Cool. Let's go uncle
# 走嘛
I'm here
# 要抖一哈
Need to shake it slightly
# 蘸一点水
Dip some water
# 这样抓住它
hold it this way
# 就可以下去（锅）了
And you can dip it in the oil
# 先把鱼头丢下去
Drop the head first
# 感觉炸硬了之后
When you feel its shape hardened
# 这样提着它
Hold it like this
# 抓住这样翻过来
And turn it around
# 这样抓住它
Hold it this way
# 然后把它放下去 就可以了
And drop it
# 然后这个也把它丢下去
This one drop in as well
# 然后把它漏起来
Then "strainer "it up
# 看 漂不漂亮嘛
See, isn't it pretty?
# 放这个番茄（酱）
Some ketchup
# 白糖
white sugar
# 放点这个白醋
As well as this clear vinegar
# 然后再少放一点盐巴
A little salt
# 这个要等它慢慢熬
It needs to be brewed slowly
# 然后把这个（鱼）摆在这里面
And you lay this (fish) in this tray
# 好 我来
Cool, I'll do it
# 再放点这个热油
A little warm oil
# 放这个热油下去
This warm oil in
# 好 关火
Ok. Turn off the fire
# 来 四伯爷尝哈看
Come on uncle, have a taste
# 试一哈嘛
Have a try!
# 这个汁的比例
This sauce
# 我们调到糖跟醋1：1都可以
is half sugar and half vinegar
# 吃起来不酸也不甜
Thus it taste neither too sour or too sweet
# 如果你们想吃甜的就多加糖
If you prefer sweet taste use more sugar
# 想吃酸一点就多加醋
More vinegar for a stronger sour taste
# 好不好吃
How do you like it?
# 跟西红柿那个味道样
It's like the taste of tomato
# 就是番茄 番茄酱
There is tomato, tomato sauce
# 这个成本不高
The cost for the raw material of this dish is not much
# 一条鱼的话两斤多
A fish over 2 jin
# 大概20块钱左右
is about 20 yuan
# 然后就是其他成本我跟你说高在哪里
And there are other expenses. I'll tell you what the high price consists in
# 看到吧这一盆粉
Do you see, this tray of starch
# 这里这个粉我算它八块钱一斤
I will count it as 8 yuan per jin
# 两斤的话就去了16（块）
It takes 16 yuan for 2 jin
# 然后还有什么
And what
# 还有这个宽油
And this "Kuan You" (lit. broad oil)
# 这个油就去了半桶
Half bucket of oil disappears
# 这个油我估计也要几十块钱
It at least costs many ten yuan
# 这个菜的成本的话
So the cost of making this dish
# 如果你只做一个菜
If you only cook one dish
# 这个菜只做一次
You just make it once
# 成本就投得非常高
It would be very costly
# 大概成本是预计在100块钱左右
I estimate it would be about 100 yuan
# 所以你们在餐厅吃这个菜
# 几十 88呀 98
How many tens? 88 yuan? 98?
# 真不贵
It is actually not expensive
# 好不好
Okay?
# 你吃一哈看 看吃得出味道来不哦
Have a taste, see if you can detect the flavour?
# 喊你说哈看 说得准不
You say it, see if it's accurate
# 我说得准啥子哦
How accurate can I say?
# 是啥子味道
What flavour is it?
# 也算酸噶
It's basically sour
# 酸酸甜甜的
sweet and sour
# 好吃安
Tasty
# 就是一个酸甜味的
It is a sweet and sour taste
# 好吃
Delicious
# 多吃点
Have more if you like
# 真的呀 真的好吃
Really. It's indeed delicious
# 真的整得安逸
It's really nice
# 吃 好吃
- Go on - Tasty!
# 好了本期视频就到这里了
Okay. This is all for today's video
# 想做的 不怕妈打得可以试一下
If you wanna try, and are not afraid of the anger of your mom, you can have a try
# 偶尔一次可以
Just once
# 不要经常这么干
Don't do this too often
# 经常这么干
You don't have the money
# 没那么多本钱
to do so
# 不太适合
It's not fitting
# 好 就到这里
Okay. I'll stop here
# 拜拜
Bye bye!
Bye!